<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Not <strike>Fired</strike> Programmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-06T07:26:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ed Tretyakov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to rewamp this into something new...]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/time-to-rewamp-this-into-something-new-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-06T07:17:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/time-to-rewamp-this-into-something-new-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So it is more than one year go from time I get lost in my dreams about great remote job. And today I decide to cleanup this debris and create on top of it something new.</p>

<p>Dunno what it will be, but, for now, I have a job, I have something to eat and my mind still in great condition! New ideas? New themes? New crazy thinhs? Aww yeah, and I like this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress is fun!]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/26/octopress-is-fun/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-26T04:20:14+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/26/octopress-is-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, it&rsquo;s really new way to maintain your blog. Forget about wordpress or any another and mind-broken overweight piece of PHP code, self-hosted blogs, site maintaining, lost database passwords, extremely high traffic from page with your kitty pic and alarms from provider about &ldquo;extending your plan immediately!&rdquo; and so on. You just don&rsquo;t need it anymore.</p>

<p>Github account, some basic ruby/DNS knowledge (and as i seen - it&rsquo;s more about duck typing copy-pasted commands to shell) - and you ready to go!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I don&rsquo;t want to retell everything that describe Octopress install guide and Jekyll internals. The basics of this blog engines can be described with simple words - everything is pre-generated and committed to Github pages as completely static site with all pages relinking and so on. Like a static cache instead of dynamic page generation (like Wordpress).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s why blogs on Jekyll-based engines is blazing-fast. And with Github protection you can be sure that your blog will be safe and alive in 99% of problems. I really believe in capabilities of Github team - dat guys know how to cook everything tasty.</p>

<p>Where is no any problem with customization and custom themes - just type some commands from your choosen theme site (like i did with Slim theme) - and it will be installed properly. Wanna change it? Go and edit simple HTML templates.</p>

<p>Even comments exist for this Blogs! Thanks to Disqus.</p>

<p>But event better is blogging itself - markdown is perfect choice for this as for me and simple editing of pre-generated files is fun. Preview on your local host is available, so you can easily fix somethnig before post.</p>

<p>Yea, I was amazed how simple and easy Octopress is. So, wanna try something new? Really hackable, easy-to-use and absolutely programmer&rsquo;s way to blog? Go and checkout <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> now - it really worth a try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Update - 26.05]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/26/daily-update-26-dot-05/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-26T04:19:48+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/26/daily-update-26-dot-05</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Days without job:</strong> 26</p>

<p><strong>Cover letters and CV sent to</strong>: Autodesk (no remote positions, will be dropped with 95% chance, but hope dies last), Bark.com, Datastax (I hate Jobvite CV submit form - it not allow to post PDF files! In 2015, CARL!), Imgur (i love it, but did not expect too much - no remote positions, so my application in 95% chance will be dropped), Automattic (former WordPress developer), Kissmetrics, Buffer.com</p>

<p><strong>First letter received:</strong> Eyeo.com (Developer of AdBlockPlus, requested some info about my JS/Python/OSS background. Seems like HR manager didn&rsquo;t open my CV at all. So I described a little my experience and now I hope this letter will be useful).</p>

<p><strong>On Hold:</strong> CurrencyFair, Gravity4 (responded with denial to my CV, but this stuff so damn hot, so I founded this company on Angels list and try one more time)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's all about money - CurrencyFair]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/25/its-all-about-money-currencyfair/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-25T07:52:41+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/25/its-all-about-money-currencyfair</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, CurrencyFair. Really impressive and promising company from Dublin, Ireland. Try to help you exchange your money at minimal cost. And, yeah - Irishmen! Remember good days when one of Irish bikers visited my city and decide to show, how Car Bomb works - dat was really funny day. If you want to know little bit more about this company - visit <a href="https://www.currencyfair.com/about-us/">About Us</a> section. But dat gentleman with tie is little scary. Or just go and read <a href="http://tech.currencyfair.com/2015/03/19/engineering-hiring-challenges/#.VWK5QGSqqko">blog post</a> about this test app. Really interesting.</p>

<p>Did not remember where I found post about careers in CurrencyFair and still don&rsquo;t know, if remote position is acceptable (and it will be another sad moment if not) - but guys sended to me google docs link to test application requirements. As i said - digging into some stuff for me is much more better compared to overclicking on job sites and so on.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>As test application this project require any candidate to create little trading application. Everything as usual - API endpoint with message consumer about successfull trades, some sort of message processor on the backend to analyze this stuff and representation of processed data on frontend. Each part has some &ldquo;experience levels&rdquo; and can be done in various ways. And you as job seeker completely free in choices of platform, language, tech stack and everythnig else related.</p>

<p>One more very tricky thing about this application - everythnig must be published to Github before final submit. So&hellip; What we gonna do as first step? Right! In few minutes after reading requirements I start browsing github search with &ldquo;currencyfair&rdquo; keyword in it. Some gems was found, but most of test projects had some issues as for me and choices of known for me tools was questionable.</p>

<p>Like <a href="https://github.com/ktunkiewicz/cfdemo">Kamil Tunkiewicz</a> app (btw this guy is already employed at CF) - really good demo, but why Node.JS as consumer? I don&rsquo;t think that mixin of languages is nice and buzz about Node furious speed is little bit overbumped nowadays. And startup scripts for daemons not the RHEL-way or Unix-way done. Kamil done good job with Statistics analyze (and seems like this is my weak part of test), but presentation can be better. And empty git history - is this man really programmed whole stuff with simgle shot? But I will put my hat off - this guy is cooked Ratchet for WS messages broadcasting. (But still with usual way with ZMQ, as i see, but I didn&rsquo;t find anythnig related to Ratchet in the sources. Probably just need to ask).</p>

<p>After quick analyze of tools people used and tech all this stuff based on in one thnig i mentioned - nobody uses some dev environment. This is not about composer / npm / pypi / any other dependency resolving tool. This is mostly about environment itself. When I looked at glance to the things that CF used to work with my smile start shining. Vagrant, Chef, DC dedication, om-nom-nom - everythnig was so damn familiar. And nobody from github didn&rsquo;t try to go with this.</p>

<p>Sure using Chef even this is chef-solo is time expensive, but that days and now I have lots of free time. And some of my things related to Gentoo is already applied to Chef cookbooks - so I  know I can handle this. Sure i&rsquo;m not a rockstar, but wannabe rockstar is even better!</p>

<p>With everything else I decide to separate every component and go with PHP-prototyped daemons. Because I like to kill childs, mwahahah. Sorry, just kiddin. Daemons are very flexible and did not overweight whole project structure. PHP prototypes of already working daemons can be developed really fast and easy - I swear I&rsquo;m spend much more time in Chef configuring compared to my cfdaemon programing itself. And PEAR already have very nice library to work with daemons.</p>

<p>Daemons need some sort of pipe between each other, and Beanstalkd was chosen as this pipe. Really fast, scalable and easy-to-use memcache protocol based queue.</p>

<p>I decide that for my purposes of websocket server Ratchet is very monstrous so I choose Wrench as little bit more specialized tool. And it work like a charm.</p>

<p>For my shame I did not spent too much time on analytics of currency values and trades done so far.</p>

<p>My basic workflow in my imagination on that time was next: Something submit new trade to endpoint (Slim PHP framework, filtering, immediate putting of new job into queue), Analytics daemon process new message, do all the stuff and pass it to the next tube (CFDaemon, basicly do some digits play and put it into memcache, and into MySQL just for permanent storaging), Websocket&rsquo;s server receive new message from pipe and pass it to frontend (CFSocket / Wrench, if someone is already connected to frontend), frontend blink country on the global map and display some info about hovered country (Raphael.js. Try it!).</p>

<p>And everything is cooked with Chef in Vagrant'ed box. For me this was the point and some kind of &ldquo;Cherry on top of cake&rdquo;. To be honest - writing right recipe for Chef was most time-consuming task it this test. Didn&rsquo;t researched capabilites of recipes testing, but it was really fun to remember everythnig after my battle with &ldquo;clustertoy&rdquo; (I will write a little post about it later). For everyone who will follow my path - use Berkshelf, Luke! Really helpful utility to maintain recipe dependencies and great time-saver.</p>

<p>For whole test i&rsquo;ve spent around 15 hours (2-3 hours per day) and few litres of coffee. And that was really fun. Dunno what to describe - please review everything at <a href="https://github.com/elhsmart/currencyfair">https://github.com/elhsmart/currencyfair</a> and ping me, if you will have any questions related.</p>

<p>After this i just installed vagrant-digitalocean plugin, deployed everythnig to DigitalOcean and submitted my app with google docs form from test requirements. Dunno why the guys from CF promise to answer in two days, but I&rsquo;m still waiting for response/review and hope it will not be lost in debris.</p>

<p>So, it&rsquo;s time to move forward! Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduce yourself please...]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/24/introduce-yourself-please/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-24T06:31:10+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/24/introduce-yourself-please</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, this is happened. I was fired.</p>

<p>Hello everyone, my name is Ed Tretyakov, I&rsquo;m PHP/JS LAMP fullstack dev and this shiny github blog is a little story about my life after breaking with my Dreamjob. I was working for DeviantArt little bit more that 1 year and was fired less than a month ago. And this was not about my skills or exp as my manager said - company just refocusing it needs. And I don&rsquo;t needed anymore. Sad smile must be here, lol.</p>

<p>Why i&rsquo;m here?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>From the beginning this blog main purpose is to keep my head cool and one more try to analyze a little my mistakes in the long journey to search a new job (I hope it will be my next Dreamjob). To be honest with every failed attempt my mood get lower and lower and I just start to think that somethnig is wrong with me.</p>

<p>One more important thing (but I did not expect too much here) - maybe someone from companies, who answered to me with denial of single damn attempt with some easy-to-send template emails (from last emails - like Wikimedia talent search team, who answered with &ldquo;we have decided not to proceed with your candidacy&rdquo; and Formstack, who answered with &ldquo;we have chosen to pursue other candidates that better fit the needs of the role.&rdquo;) will see one day my posts and feel my pain too. Because it&rsquo;s fuckin hard to read this stuff without simple piece of understanding, where exactly I&rsquo;m failed. CV not interesting? Low experience? Not perfect language? Wrong skin color? Magnetic storms? Anything else? Nobody answer. And all this templates are sended from no-reply@&hellip; So, while talking to companies in the usual way is hard - maybe this blog helps? At least I hope so&hellip;</p>

<p>And as for me this is really big problem. Ain&rsquo;t nobody give a single fuckin chance to proove yor skills or experience or passion to coding and engineering. Nobody. So far I seen only one company (CurrencyFair) who ask for some kind of test and while in the test submit form they promised to answer in 2 days - week passed and still nobody visit it.</p>

<p>I will try to analyze what I&rsquo;ve done so far and what steps was processed with every company I&rsquo;m tried. It&rsquo;s interesting and if I can design and create some things in the process - that will be really awesome. And, yeah, I don&rsquo;t want to freeze and want to express somethnig new to me too, so why not? Freezed, bored, tired and upset programmer is dead for community and market, and I don&rsquo;t want to be dat dead thing.</p>

<p>I want to close this blog when my job will find me, but who knows? Maybe I will like it and just change a title.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>

<p>P.S. Sorry for my english, I live in Ukraine and not native speaker, so sometimes my language can be really bad.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
