<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ideas | Not <strike>Fired</strike> Programmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/categories/ideas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-10T17:31:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ed Tretyakov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cars sellers photo helper]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/10/cars-sellers-photo-helper/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-10T17:26:15+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/10/cars-sellers-photo-helper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is something interesting to leverage time and money for nothnig during photo shots of your old fashioned stylish car.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve imagine something like tubular spherical cunstruction with tiny motorized drive unit with stepper motor and wifi module to take
shots from GoPro / any other camera from different angles. And this will help you to take photos from top spot points and other places, whis is not accessible during
your stand near car.</p>

<p>Another solution - creage custom software for drone, which can apply focing data to camera and take shots on the fly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Idea: Automatic plains spotter]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/idea-automatic-plains-spotter/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-06T07:29:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/idea-automatic-plains-spotter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>And this blog will contain ideas for future projects. Or somethnig similar.</p>

<p>One of them - automatic photo/video camera for plain spotters on the site of Airport with plane type / date of arrival and intellectual camera tergeting system to follow plane during landing / take off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to rewamp this into something new...]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/time-to-rewamp-this-into-something-new-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-06T07:17:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/time-to-rewamp-this-into-something-new-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So it is more than one year go from time I get lost in my dreams about great remote job. And today I decide to cleanup this debris and create on top of it something new.</p>

<p>Dunno what it will be, but, for now, I have a job, I have something to eat and my mind still in great condition! New ideas? New themes? New crazy things? Aww yeah, and I like this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
