<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | Not <strike>Fired</strike> Programmer]]></title>
  <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-10T17:31:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ed Tretyakov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to rewamp this into something new...]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/time-to-rewamp-this-into-something-new-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-06T07:17:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2017/02/06/time-to-rewamp-this-into-something-new-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So it is more than one year go from time I get lost in my dreams about great remote job. And today I decide to cleanup this debris and create on top of it something new.</p>

<p>Dunno what it will be, but, for now, I have a job, I have something to eat and my mind still in great condition! New ideas? New themes? New crazy things? Aww yeah, and I like this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress is fun!]]></title>
    <link href="http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/26/octopress-is-fun/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-26T04:20:14+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://elhsmart.github.io/blog/2015/05/26/octopress-is-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, it&rsquo;s really new way to maintain your blog. Forget about wordpress or any another and mind-broken overweight piece of PHP code, self-hosted blogs, site maintaining, lost database passwords, extremely high traffic from page with your kitty pic and alarms from provider about &ldquo;extending your plan immediately!&rdquo; and so on. You just don&rsquo;t need it anymore.</p>

<p>Github account, some basic ruby/DNS knowledge (and as i seen - it&rsquo;s more about duck typing copy-pasted commands to shell) - and you ready to go!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I don&rsquo;t want to retell everything that describe Octopress install guide and Jekyll internals. The basics of this blog engines can be described with simple words - everything is pre-generated and committed to Github pages as completely static site with all pages relinking and so on. Like a static cache instead of dynamic page generation (like Wordpress).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s why blogs on Jekyll-based engines is blazing-fast. And with Github protection you can be sure that your blog will be safe and alive in 99% of problems. I really believe in capabilities of Github team - dat guys know how to cook everything tasty.</p>

<p>Where is no any problem with customization and custom themes - just type some commands from your choosen theme site (like i did with Slim theme) - and it will be installed properly. Wanna change it? Go and edit simple HTML templates.</p>

<p>Even comments exist for this Blogs! Thanks to Disqus.</p>

<p>But event better is blogging itself - markdown is perfect choice for this as for me and simple editing of pre-generated files is fun. Preview on your local host is available, so you can easily fix somethnig before post.</p>

<p>Yea, I was amazed how simple and easy Octopress is. So, wanna try something new? Really hackable, easy-to-use and absolutely programmer&rsquo;s way to blog? Go and checkout <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> now - it really worth a try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
